voicestar.com 2015-06-12

# Privacy Statement : Company : Marchex

Marchex, Inc., its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively “we” or “Marchex”) respect your privacy. This privacy statement applies to the information Marchex collects on [ www.marchex.com](http://www.marchex.com/), including the site’s customer log-in areas (the “Site”). This privacy statement describes how we collect and use the personal information we collect on our Site, and describes the choices you have regarding our use of your personal information. This privacy policy does not apply to the services Marchex provides to or on behalf of its customers.

Marchex has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe US-EU Safe Harbor Privacy and TRUSTed Cloud program. The TRUSTe certification covers only our collection, use and disclosure of information we collect through our Site: [ www.marchex.com](http://www.marchex.com/) and from customers of the Marchex Call Analytics services. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern, you should contact us at [privacy@marchex.com](mailto:privacy@marchex.com). If Marchex does not satisfactorily address your concern, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

_**What Information Do We Collect?**_

We may request that an entity applying for an account with Marchex provide us with certain personal information (such as name, email address, etc.) relevant to our provision of services to the entity. We also collect login and registration information from our customers so that they may access their account information via the Site. We also collect information automatically from customers and Site users, as described below.

We may use the information we collect on our Site for business-related purposes, such as to register and administer your account, to answer to your customer service requests, to communicate with you about your account, and to send you information about products, services and promotions we think you may be interested in. You can opt out of receiving marketing emails from us by following the opt out instructions contained in any such email. If you opt out, we may still send you emails about your account and the services you have requested.

_**How Do We Use Cookies and Other Monitoring Technologies?**_

_Cookies_. Like most sites, for account management purposes, Marchex may use session ID cookies and persistent cookies, as well as web beacons and other monitoring technologies to compile statistics about Site users. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities at our Site. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function.

_Local Storage Objects_. We may use Local Storage Objects (“LSOs”), including Flash LSOs, to store your Site preferences and to personalize your visit. LSOs are different from browser cookies because of the amount and type of data stored. Typically, you cannot control, delete, or disable the acceptance of LSOs through your web browser. For more information on Flash LSOs, or to learn how to manage your settings for Flash LSOs, go to the Adobe Flash Player Help Page. 

_Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies_. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (a.k.a. web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site to, among other things, track the activities of Site visitors, help us manage content, and compile statistics about Site usage. We and our third-party service providers also may use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers, to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed, and track whether our emails are forwarded. 

_Third-Party Analytics_. We use automated devices and third party applications, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Site. We and our third party providers also may use other analytic means, such as clear GIFs to evaluate our Site. We use these tools to help us improve our Site, performance and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services. Such third parties may combine the information that we provide about you with other information that they have collected. This Policy does not cover such third parties’ use of the data.

Cookies, web beacons and related monitoring technologies enable us to track user trends, preferences and patterns. We may also receive and record information from your computer and browser, including your IP address, pages(s) you visited and keyword searches you conducted on our Site. The information helps us provide improved services, develop new products, and provided customized content, including targeted advertising. 

_**Third-Party Ad Networks**_

We use third parties, such as network advertisers, to display Marchex ads on third-party websites. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your use of our Site and other third-party website and mobile applications. This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements by displaying ads for products and services in which you might be interested. Third-party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors, and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs, and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third-party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party’s specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third-party advertisers with information about your usage of our Site. We do not share your personal information collected on our Site, such as name or email address, or other personal information with these third parties. These third parties may collect IP address and related site usage data; however we don’t permit them to collect your name, contact information or other personally identifiable information through our Site.

You may opt out of many website third-party ad networks, including those operated by members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). For more information regarding this practice by NAI members and DAA members, including how to opt out of third-party ad networks operated by NAI and DAA members, please visit their respective websites: [www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp/) (NAI) and [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) (DAA). If you are located in the European Union, you may opt out of many ad networks by visiting [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

Opting out of one or more NAI member or DAA member networks (many of which will be the same) only means that those members no longer will deliver targeted content or ads to you. It does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content or ads on our Site or other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing. Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit this opt-out page, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different computer or change web browsers, your opt-out may no longer be effective. Additional information is available on the NAI and DAA websites accessible by the above links.

_**What about Do-Not-Track options?**_

Currently, our Site does not honor browser requests not to be tracked. 

_**Links to Other Sites?**_

The Marchex website contains links to other sites. We are not responsible or liable for the privacy practices or content of such sites since we do not control them.

_**With Whom Do We Share Information?**_

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy, or as otherwise consented by you.

Marchex may share non-personal information about our users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties. Such non-personally identifiable information may include, for example, your IP address, pages(s) you visited and keyword searches you conducted on our Site. This information may allow such third parties to provide you customized advertising.

In addition, Marchex may partner with other parties in connection with the various services offered on our Site, such as credit card processors or email delivery services. In such instances, we may share limited personal information that is necessary for the third party to provide its services. These companies are only permitted to use this information on our behalf.

Marchex may also provide personal information when disclosure may be required by law (e.g., subpoenas, search warrants and court orders), to enforce the terms of our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service, and as evidence in litigation in which we are involved. We may also determine that such action is reasonably necessary to protect our or another party’s rights, property, or well-being. This action may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud detection or protection, or in other situations involving suspicious or illegal activities.

_**Business Transfers?**_

In the event of a transfer of ownership of Marchex, such as acquisition by or merger with another company, or in the case of bankruptcy, a user’s information may be transferred to the acquiring company. 

_**User Access**_

Marchex customers may change or delete most of their personal information on record with us, by logging into your account and updating it. If you have any questions or need assistance in changing, deleting, or accessing some information, you may contact us at [ privacy@marchex.com](mailto:privacy@marchex.com). We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

We will retain your information (including information we collect on behalf of our Clients) for as long as your or that Client’s account is active or as needed to provide you services, and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, or as otherwise reasonably necessary for our business purposes.

_**Information Related to Data Collected for our Clients**_

In Marchex’s capacity as a provider of analytics services to our business customers and clients (“Clients” herein), we collect information from our Clients’ end users, which may include personal information. Marchex has no direct relationship with its Clients’ end users, and will use and process end user personal information only under the direction of our Clients. 

End users and customers of Marchex Clients seeking access to any personal information we have collected on behalf of a Client, should direct their query to the Marchex Client (the data controller). Our Clients may request that we delete any personal information that we have collected on their behalf, and where reasonable we will comply with such requests within 30 days. However, residual copies of end user data may be retained in archived or backup form.

_**Marketing Communications**_

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to you, including newsletters. You may opt out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the email. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you emails about your account or any purchases.

_**Security.**_

The security of your personal information is important to us. We have implemented safeguards, including where appropriate SSL encryption for sensitive data in transmission, to protect the personal information submitted to us. No method of transmission over the Internet, or electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Site, you can contact us at[ privacy@marchex.com](mailto:privacy@marchex.com).

_**Blog.**_

Our Site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. _To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at[privacy@marchex.com](mailto:privacy@marchex.com)_. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

_**Social Media Widgets.**_

Our Site includes social media features, such as Facebook and Twitter buttons and widgets. These features may collect information, including your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing such features.

_**Safe Harbor**_

With respect to the personal data received from the European Union and Switzerland related to the Marchex Call Analytics and related services, Marchex complies with the U.S. - E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. Marchex has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement with respect to these services. To view our Safe Harbor Privacy Policy, click [here](http://www.marchex.com/legal/safeharbor). To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Marchex’s certification, please visit [ http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/).

_**Consent and Changes to this Privacy Statement?**_

By using our Site, you consent to the collection and use of your information as we have outlined in this privacy statement and consent to our Terms of Use. Use of Marchex services is subject to separate terms and condition. Marchex may decide to change this privacy statement from time to time. If and when we do, we will post the changes on this page so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

_**Who Can I Ask If I Have Additional Questions?**_

Feel free to contact us at any time with any questions you may have regarding our privacy statement.

Marchex, Inc.   
520 Pike Street, Suite 2000  
Seattle, WA 98101  
Office: 206-331-3300  
Fax: 206-331-3696  
Email: [privacy@marchex.com](mailto:privacy@marchex.com)

_Effective November 7, 2014_
